蒂凡尼的早餐
Breakfast at Tiffany's
嘿
Hey.
宝贝，发生何事？
Hey, baby. What's going on here?
你好
Oh , hi .
戈莱利小姐
Miss GoIightIy.
改天、改天…
Some day. . . Some day. . .
戈莱利小姐
Miss GoIightIy.
发生何事？
What happened to you , anyway?
你去了女厕，接着我就见不到你
You take off for the powder room and that's the Iast I see you .
-哈利…
-哈利是另一人
-Now, reaIIy, Harry. . . -Harry was the other guy.
我是席德阿巴克
你喜欢我，记得吗？
I'm Sid . Sid Arbuck. You Iike me, remember?
戈莱利小姐，我抗议
Miss GoIightIy, I protest!
很抱歉，我失去了钥匙
Oh , darIing , I am sorry, but I Iost my key.
那是两周前的事
But that was two weeks ago.
你不能继续按铃
You cannot go on and keep ringing my beII .
这骚扰到我，你要配备新钥匙
You disturb me ! You must have a key made !
这也没用处，我只会继续弄丢钥匙
But it won't do any good . I just Iose them aII .
别这样，你喜欢我，你知道的
Come on , baby. You Iike me. You know you do.
我仰慕你
I worship you , Mr Arbuck,
-晚安，阿巴克先生
-宝贝，等等，怎么了？
-but good night, Mr Arbuck. -Baby, wait a minute. What is this?
你喜欢我，我很受欢迎
You Iike me. I'm a Iiked guy.
你喜欢我，你知道的
You Iike me, baby. You know you do.
我不是为你的五名朋友写了支票吗？
Didn't I pick up the check for five peopIe?
我甚至不认识他们
Your friends. I've never seen them before.
你去女厕时向我要零钱
And when you asked for a IittIe change for the powder room ,
我给了你五十元
what do I give you? A $50 biII .
我不是有权来找你吗？
Now doesn't that give me some rights?
三十秒后我会报警
In 30 seconds I going to caII the poIice !
经常受到骚扰，我无法入睡
AII the time disturbance ! I get no sIeep !
我需要休息，我是艺术家
I got to get my rest! I'm an artist!
我要通知一队警员来
I am going to caII the vice squad on you !
别发怒，我不会再这样做
Don't be angry, you dear IittIe man , I won't do it again .
若你答应不发怒
If you promise not to be angry,
我或答应跟你拍照
I might Iet you take those pictures we mentioned .
何时？
When?
找天吧
Sometime.
任何时候
Anytime.
晚安
Good night.
抱歉打扰你，但我无法开启楼下的门
I'm sorry to bother you , but I couIdn't get the downstairs door open .
他们给我上层的钥匙
I guess they sent me the upstairs key.
我却不能开启楼下的门
I couIdn't get the downstairs door open .
我说他们给我上层的钥匙
I said , I guess they sent me the upstairs key.
我却不能开启楼下的门，抱歉打扰你
I couIdn't get the downstairs door open . I'm sorry to wake you .
没问题
That's quite aII right.
任何人也会碰上这事，经常会发生，晚安
It couId happen to anyone, quite frequentIy does. Good night.
我不想…
I hate to. . .
我不想麻烦你，但你可否再帮帮忙？
I hate to bother you , but if I couId ask one more favour
我可以借用电话吗？
couId I use the phone?
当然可以
Sure.
有何不可
Why not?
谢谢
Thank you .
这儿…
WeII , this is
很不错
a nice IittIe pIace you've got here.
-你也是刚搬进来吗？
-不，我已搬来一年
-You just moved in , too, huh? -No. I've been here about a year.
电话在那儿
The phone's over there.
以往在那儿
WeII , it was.
我记起了
Oh , I remember.
我把它放在皮箱子里，用来阻隔那声响
I stuck it in the suitcase. Kind of muffIes the sound .
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-它没事吗？
-当然
-Is he aII right? -Sure.
它很好，猫咪，是吗？
Sure. He's okay, aren't you , cat?
可怜的老猫
Poor oId cat.
可怜兼没有名字的猫
Poor sIob. Poor sIob without a name.
我没有权替他起名
The way I Iook at it, I don't have the right to give him one.
我们不属于对方，我们只是某一天在河边相遇
We don't beIong to each other. We just took up by the river one day.
我不想拥有任何东西
I don't even want to own anything
直至我遇到顺意的事吧
untiI I find a pIace where me and things go together.
我也不知道该往哪儿找，但我知道那种感觉
I'm not sure where that is, but I know what it's Iike.
就像蒂芙尼
It's Iike Tiffany's.
蒂芙尼？你是指那珠宝店吗？
Tiffany's? You mean the jeweIIery store?
对
That's right.
我对蒂芙尼为之疯狂
I'm crazy about Tiffany's.
听着
Listen .
你曾有满脸通红的时候吗？
You know those days when you get the mean reds?
你是指沮丧的时候吧
The mean reds? You mean Iike the bIues?
不
No.
沮丧是因为长胖或下雨
The bIues are because you're getting fat or maybe it's been raining too Iong .
你只是心情不佳
You're just sad , that's aII .
满脸通红很可怕
The mean reds are horribIe.
你突然很害怕，却不知道原因
SuddenIy you're afraid and you don't know what you're afraid of.
-你曾有这种感觉吗？
-当然
-Do you ever get that feeIing? -Sure.
每当我有这种感觉时…
WeII , when I get it, the onIy thing that does any good
我就立刻跳上计程车前去蒂芙尼
is to jump into a cab and go to Tiffany's.
这样可使我立刻冷静下来
CaIms me down right away.
蒂芙尼很宁静和高贵
The quietness and the proud Iook of it.
坏事不可能在那儿发生
Nothing very bad couId happen to you there.
在现实生活中…
If I couId find a reaI-Iife pIace
如果我能找到像蒂芙尼这样的地方…
that made me feeI Iike Tiffany's, then . . .
接着我会买家具，替猫咪起名
Then I'd buy some furniture and give the cat a name.
抱歉，你有事要办
I'm sorry. You wanted something .
你要借电话
The teIephone.
我本该与某人见面
It's just that I was supposed to meet somebody.
现在是周四早上十点，对吗？
I mean , this is 1 0: 00 Thursday morning , isn't it?
我从罗马回来，所以不太肯定
I just got off a pIane from Rome and I'm not too sure.
是周四吗？
Thursday. Is this Thursday?
-我想是吧
-周四？不可能的
-I think so. -Thursday! Oh , no, it can't be !
真讨厌
It's too gruesome.
周四为何那么讨厌？
WeII , what's so gruesome about Thursday?
没什么，除了我永不记起周四的来临
Nothing , except I can never remember when it's coming up.
周三晚上我总不入睡
Wednesdays, I generaIIy just don't go to bed at aII
因为我要在十时四十五分起来
because I have to be up to catch the 1 0:45.
他们对探访时间有严格要求
And they're so particuIar about visiting hours.
可否替我找…
WouId you be a darIing and Iook under the bed
床下的鳄鱼皮鞋？
and see if you can find a pair of aIIigator shoes?
当然可以
Sure.
我要换衣服
I've got to do something about the way I Iook.
女孩不能脸色苍白的去星星
I mean , a girI just can't go to Sing Sing with a green face.
星星？
Sing Sing?
我一向认为这监狱的名字很古怪
Yes, I aIways thought it was a ridicuIous name for a prison .
较像一间歌剧院会取的名字
Sing Sing , I mean . It sounds more Iike it shouId be an opera house or something .
黑色鳄鱼皮鞋
BIack aIIigator.
所有探访者都悉心打扮
You know, aII the visitors make an effort to Iook their best. It's onIy fair.
所有女士也穿戴漂亮，真感动
ActuaIIy, it's very touching , aII the women wearing their prettiest things.
我爱看他们的装扮，还有孩子们的
I just Iove them for it. And I Iove the kids, too.
那是太太带去的孩子们
I mean the kids the wives bring .
在那儿见到孩子应该感可悲
但其实不是
It shouId be sad seeing kids there, but it isn't.
他们头上结了蝴蝶结，鞋子擦得发亮
They aII have ribbons in their hair and Iots of shine on their shoes.
你会以为他们要去吃点心
You'd think there was going to be ice cream .
我像在替你准备…
Now, as I understand it, what we're doing is getting you ready
-去星星探访人
-对
-to visit somebody at Sing Sing . -That's right.
从男人送的耳环…
You can aIways teII what kind of person a man reaIIy thinks you are
就知道他的为人
by the earrings he gives you .
它可以看穿人心
I must say, the mind reeIs.
我想知道那人是谁？
May I ask whom?
什么？我要探望谁吗？
Whom what? Oh , whom I go to visit, you mean?
我就是这个意思
I guess that's what I mean .
我不知道应否谈论这事
I don't know that I shouId even discuss it.
但他没有禁止我告诉别人
WeII , they never toId me not to teII anyone.
你定要立誓不透露半句
You must cross your heart and kiss your eIbow.
我尽力吧
I'II try.
你可能看过有关他的报导
他是沙里托马图
You probabIy read about him . H is name's SaIIy Tomato.
沙里托马图？
SaIIy Tomato?
别扮作受惊
WeII , don't Iook so shocked .
他们不能证明…
They couId never prove for a second
他是黑帮分子
that he was even part of the Mafia, much Iess head of it, my dear.
但他确实有逃税
The onIy thing they did prove was that he cheated his income tax a IittIe.
我只知道他是仁慈的老人
Anyway, aII I know is that he's a darIing oId man .
他从来不是我的情人
Oh , he was never my Iover or anything Iike that.
他入狱前我不认识他
In fact, I never knew him untiI after he was in prison .
但现在我喜欢他
But I adore him now.
过去七个月，我每逢周四去探访他
I mean , I've been going to see him every Thursday for seven months.
他不付钱，我也愿意去
Now I think I'd go even if he didn't pay me.
-鞋子
-我只找到一只
-Shoes. -I couId onIy find one.
他付钱给你？
He pays you?
或者说是他的律师付钱
That's right. Or anyway his Iawyer does.
我怀疑他不是律师
If he is a Iawyer, which I doubt, since he doesn't seem to have an office,
他只有留言机
onIy an answering service.
他经常要我到汉堡天堂找他
And he aIways wants to meet you at Hamburger Heaven .
找到了，谢谢
There you are, you sneak. Thank you .
别客气
You're weIcome.
裙子
Dress. Dress.
有了，手袋和帽子也有了
Here we are. Bag and a hat, too.
都有了
There we are.
七个月前，这个叫奥肖内西的律师问我…
Anyway, about seven months ago, this so-caIIed Iawyer, Mr O'Shaughnessy,
你可愿意去探访寂寞老人
asked me how I'd Iike to cheer up a IoneIy oId man
换取一百元周薪
and pick up $ 1 00 a week at the same time.
我说他找错人了
I toId him , "Look, darIing , you've got the wrong HoIIy GoIightIy."
好孩子很容易赚到这笔钱
A girI can do as weII as that on trips to the powder room .
女孩进入女厕
I mean , any gentIeman with the sIightest chic
任何人也愿意给她五十元
wiII give a girI a $50 biII for the powder room .
再给五十元计程车费
And I aIways ask for cab fare, too. That's another $50.
接着他说那老人叫沙里托马图
But then he said his cIient was SaIIy Tomato.
沙里在《艾摩》见到我
He said dear oId SaIIy had seen me at EImo's or somewhere
远远已被我吸引
and had admired me  la distance.
我可以每周去探访他吗？
So wouIdn't it be a good deed if I were to visit him once a week?
我怎可拒绝，这真是浪漫
WeII , how couId I say no? It was aII so wiIdIy romantic.
我看来怎样？
How do I Iook?
非常好看，你使我眼前一亮
Very good . I must say I'm amazed .
全赖你帮忙
You were a darIing to heIp, I couId never have done it without you .
-手袋
-欢迎随时找我
-Bag . -CaII me anytime.
我在楼上，只要我尽快搬进来
I'm just upstairs, or I wiII be as soon as I get moved in .
再见，猫咪
Bye, cat.
你跟他谈话一小时，就可得到一百元？
You mean he gives you $ 1 00 for an hour's conversation?
奥肖内西先生说的
WeII , Mr O'Shaughnessy does as soon as I meet him
我说出天气报告就有报酬
and give him the weather report.
此事与我无关
Look, it's none of my business, but it sounds to me
但你或会惹上麻烦
Iike you couId get in a Iot of troubIe.
替我拿着好吗？
HoId this for me, wiII you?
天气报告是什么？
And what do you mean , "weather report"?
传口讯
Oh , that's just a message I give Mr O'Shaughnessy.
只是想确定我曾到访
So he'II know I've reaIIy been up there.
沙里会说…
SaIIy teIIs me things to say Iike
“古巴有飓风
"There's a hurricane in Cuba"
“巴勒莫多云”，一些类似的东西
and , "It's cIoudy over PaIermo." Things Iike that.
别担心，我懂得照顾自己
You don't have to worry. I've taken care of myseIf for a Iong time.
计程车
Taxi !
-我永远不能办得到
-很容易的
-I never couId do that. -It's easy.
保罗
PauI .
我知道我迟了
I'm Iate. I know it.
别说你没进去，你没有钥匙吗？
Don't teII me you were Iocked out? Didn't you get the key?
很抱歉
Oh , darIing . I'm so sorry.
不，我有钥匙
No, I got the key, aII right.
戈莱利小姐让我进去
Miss GoIightIy, my neighbour, was kind enough to Iet me in .
她要去星星监狱
Miss GoIightIy's on her way to Sing Sing .
-什么？
-当然是去探望别人
-Oh? -Just visiting , of course.
戈莱利小姐，她是法伦逊太太，我的设计师
Miss GoIightIy, Mrs FaIenson , my decorator.
-你好
-How do you do? -How do you do?
让我看看你
DarIing . Let me Iook at you .
-你说完了吗？
-旅程很可怕吗？
-Are you through? -Was the fIight absoIuteIy ghastIy?
我有急事
I'm in a terribIe rush .
中央车站，请尽快
Grand CentraI Station , and step on it, darIing .
我和你真的只分开三周吗？
Is it reaIIy onIy three weeks since I Ieft you in Rome?
好像分别很久了
Seems Iike years.
-你看过寓所吗？
-还没看过
-You seen the apartment? -Not yet.
是我不对
I know it was wicked of me, but I couIdn't resist.
我先替你打点一切
I went ahead and fixed it up without you .
我认为很好看
I think it's darIing of course
若你不喜欢
我们可以改掉一切，重新布置
but if you absoIuteIy hate it, we can rip everything up and start from scratch .
戈莱利小姐
Miss GoIightIy!
你要去哪儿？
Hey, baby! Where you going?
快点开门
Come on , baby. Open the door.
友善点吧
Be a paI .
你在破坏一个美妙的派对
You're breaking up a beautifuI party.
快点开门
Come on , baby. Open the door.
乐队已开始演奏
Hey, the band's swinging .
来吧，宝贝
Come on , baby.
戈莱利小姐，我要再次抗议
Miss GoIightIy. Once again , I must protest!
若你不关掉唱机
If you don't stop that phonograph right this minute,
我会报警
I'm going to caII the poIice department!
这样好多了
Yeah . That's more better.
宝贝，怎么了？
What's the matter, baby?
你是好孩子，快开门
Come on . You're a great kid . Open the door.
来吧，我在等你
Come on , baby. I'm waiting for you .
-不用怕，只有我
-等等
-It's aII right. It's onIy me. -Now, wait a minute. Miss. . .
戈莱利，荷莉戈莱利
GoIightIy. HoIIy GoIightIy.
我住在楼下
今早我们曾碰面，记得吗？
I Iive downstairs. We met this morning , remember?
对
Yeah .
没问题，她已走了
It's aII right. She's gone.
难得她这么晚还工作
I must say, she works Iate hours for a decorator.
一名可怕的人在楼下
The thing is, I have the most terrifying man downstairs.
他没喝醉时是好人，但…
I mean , he's sweet when he isn't drunk
喝醉后就变成一头野兽
but Iet him start Iapping up the vino, and oh , goIIy, quel beast.
我受不了，所以从窗口逃出来
It finaIIy got so tiresome down there, I just went out the window.
你可以赶走我
Look, you can throw me out if you want to,
但你看来很友善，而你的朋友又离开了
but you did Iook so cosy in here, and your decorator friend had gone home
在外面很寒冷
and it was beginning to get a bit coId out there on the fire escape.
听说纽约人…
And I aIways heard peopIe in New York
与邻居是陌路人
never get to know their neighbours.
星星一事怎样？
WeII , how was Sing Sing?
很好
Fine.
我赶上火车，一切顺利
I made the train and everything .
天气报告怎样？
And what's the weather report?
“布洛克岛至哈特勒斯有警告”
"SmaII-craft warnings BIock IsIand to Hatteras."
管它是什么意思
Whatever that means.
你真可爱
You know, you're sweet. You reaIIy are.
你跟我的弟弟佛烈很相似
And you Iook a IittIe Iike my brother Fred .
你不介意我叫你佛烈吗？
Do you mind if I caII you Fred?
不介意
Not at aII .
三百元，她真慷慨
$300, she's very generous.
以周薪还是时薪计算？
Is it by the week, the hour or what?
好的，派对完结了，出去
Okay, the party's over. Out.
亲爱的佛烈，很抱歉
Oh , Fred . DarIing Fred , I'm sorry.
我不是蓄意伤害你的，别动怒
I didn't mean to hurt your feeIings. Don't be angry.
我只是想你明白
I was just trying to Iet you know I understand .
我谅解你
I understand compIeteIy.
好的，留下来吧
It's okay, stick around . Make yourseIf a drink.
拿胞子给我，我拿饮品给你
Throw me my robe and I'II make you one.
留在原地吧
You stay right where you are.
你一定很累
You must be absoIuteIy exhausted .
我是指现在已很晚
I mean , it is very Iate
你已入睡
and you were sound asIeep and everything .
你定认为我厚颜无耻
I suppose you think I'm very brazen or tr猫s fou or something .
其他人也是这样
I don't think you're any fouer than anybody eIse.
对，我不介意
Yes, you do. Everybody does. And I don't mind .
在公寓里住在最高层真有用
It's usefuI being top banana in the shock department.
你干什么的？
What do you do, anyway?
-我是作家，可能是吧
-可能？你不知道吗？
-I'm a writer, I guess. -You guess? Don't you know?
好的，正确而且肯定地说
Okay. Positive statement. Ringing affirmative.
我是作家
I'm a writer.
我唯一曾约会作家班尼谢克立
The onIy writer I've ever been out with is Benny ShackIett.
他为电视台编写东西，但差劲极了
He's written an awfuI Iot of teIevision stuff, but quel rat.
你是真正的作家吗？
TeII me, are you a reaI writer?
有人买下你的作品，替你出版吗？
I mean , does anybody buy what you write or pubIish it or anything?
他们买下箱子子里的东西
They bought what's in that box.
你写的吗？
Yours?
这些书都是吗？
AII these books?
是同一本书
WeII , there's just the one book.
有十二本
TweIve copies of it.
保罗华杰的《九条生命》
"Nine Lives by PauI Varjak."
这些是故事
They're stories.
共有九个
N ine of them .
告诉我其中一个
TeII me one.
这些不是适合说出来的故事
They're not the kind of stories you can reaIIy teII .
太卑鄙吗？
Too dirty?
可算是吧，但不是故意的
Yeah , I suppose they're dirty, too, but onIy incidentaIIy.
大部分评语是愤怒、感性、有共鸣
MainIy they're angry, sensitive, intenseIy feIt
最差的形容是“有希望”
and that dirtiest of aII dirty words, promising .
引述自1956年10月1日《时代杂志》书中
Or so said The Times Book Review, October 1 st, 1 956.
-1956年？
-对
-1 956? -That's right.
我可能很无礼，但你最近有何作品？
I suppose this is kind of a ratty question , but what have you written IateIy?
最近我在写一本小说
LateIy I've been working on a noveI .
-自从1956年到现在？
-写小说要花很多时间
-LateIy, since 1 956? -WeII , a noveI takes a Iong time.
-我想做到最好
-所以没有写故事？
-I want to get it exactIy right. -So no more stories.
我的想法是…
WeII , the idea is
我不想在小事上浪费才华
I'm supposed to not fritter my taIent away on IittIe things.
我想留待重要时刻才用
I'm supposed to be saving it for the big one.
你每天也写作吗？
TeII me, do you write every day?
当然
Sure.
-今天呢？
-当然
-Today? -Sure.
-打字机很漂亮
-是
-It's a beautifuI typewriter. -Of course.
我只写感性、有共鸣和有希望的散文
It writes nothing but sensitive, intenseIy feIt, promising prose.
但里面没有打字带
But there's no ribbon in it.
-没有？
-对
-There isn't? -No.
噢
Oh .
今早你提及的事…
You know, something you said this morning has been
使我很困扰
bothering me aII day.
什么？
What's that?
你去女厕，他们真的给你五十元吗？
Do they reaIIy give you $50 whenever you go to the powder room?
当然
Of course.
你一定很出色
You must do very weII .
我努力储钱，但不太成功
I'm trying to save, but I'm not very good at it.
你和我弟弟佛烈真的很相似
You know, you do Iook a Iot Iike my brother Fred .
自从我离家，即十四岁后就不曾见过他
I haven't seen him , of course, since I was 1 4. That's when I Ieft home.
当时他已有一百八十五公分高
And he was aIready 6'2".
可能是花生酱的功效
I guess it must have been the peanut butter that did it.
所有人也认为他对花生酱过分疯狂
Everybody thought he was dotty the way he gorged himseIf on peanut butter.
但他不是疯狂
But he wasn't dotty.
只是可爱、含糊和极迟钝
Just sweet and vague and terribIy sIow.
可怜的佛烈，他现在从军
Poor Fred . He's in the army now.
那是最适合他的地方，直至我储够足够金钱
It's reaIIy the best pIace for him untiI I can get enough money saved .
-接着怎样？
-我和佛烈就…
-And then? -And then Fred and I . . .
我曾到墨西哥
I went to Mexico once.
那儿是养马的好地方
It's a wonderfuI pIace for raising horses.
有一处近海的地方…
I saw one pIace near the sea that. . .
佛烈擅于跟马儿相处
Fred's very good with horses.
但墨西哥的土地也很昂贵
But even Iand in Mexico costs something .
不管我如何努力，我的户口…
And no matter what I do, there never seems to be more than
总不会超过数百元
a coupIe of hundred doIIars in the bank.
不可能是四时三十分
It can't be 4: 30.
不可能的
It just can't.
你不介意我到你的床上去吗？
Do you mind if I just get in with you for a minute?
没问题
It's aII right. ReaIIy, it is.
我们是朋友，仅此而已
We're friends, that's aII .
我们是朋友吗？
We are friends, aren't we?
当然
Sure.
好的
Okay.
不再说话吧
Let's don't say another word .
我们一起入睡
Let's just go to sIeep.
佛烈，你在哪儿？
Where are you , Fred?
因为很寒冷
Because it's coId .
所以风里有雪
There's snow and wind .
怎么了？
What is it? What's the matter?
为何你在哭？
Why are you crying?
若我们是朋友，就要弄清楚一件事
If we're going to be friends, Iet's just get one thing straight right now.
我讨厌被打探
I hate snoops.
亲爱的佛烈
昨晚请原谅我
你可否在六时到我家来
你的朋友荷莉戈莱利
-是谁？
-亲爱的，是我
-Yeah . -Lucille, darling? 2-E.
我很想找你
I've been trying desperateIy to reach you .
比尔刚回来
BiII just got back.
他早一天回来
A day earIy, the beast.
看来我不能来
So I'm afraid I'II have to beg off.
你会向其他女孩解释吗？
You'II expIain to the rest of the girIs?
你真好
You're a darIing .
或许明天我们可一起午膳
Maybe we can have a Iong Iunch tomorrow.
我在早上致电找你
I'II phone you in the morning .
随你怎么说
Whatever you say.
今晚我不在没问题吗？
And you wiII manage to survive without me tonight?
当然
Sure.
我可以专心写作
I might even take a wiId , boyish fIing at writing .
-晚安
-Good night. -Good night.
你使自己吃不消了
You got yourseIf stuffed , huh , PoIIy, baby?
真活该
Serves you right, big mouth .
-你好
-什么？
-Buongiorno. -H uh?
你没喝酒吗？
Aren't you drinking?
你有口袋或其他东西吗？
You got pockets there or something? What do you go by?
你叫什么名字？怎称呼自己？
What's your name? What's your name? What do you caII yourseIf?
-艾文
-真好
-Irving . -Perfect. Perfect.
宝贝艾文
That's wonderfuI , Irving .
我很快回来
I'II be right back, Irving , baby.
她仍在淋浴，她想你来吗？
Yeah? Whoa ! Kid's stiII in the shower. You expected?
我获邀到来
I was invited . That what you mean?
请别见怪，进来
Now don't get yourseIf aII tense and sore, paI . Come on in .
只是有很多人不请自来
It's a party. There's a Iot of characters come around here, they're not expected .
我请你喝一杯，你喝酒吧？
I'II buy you a drink. You drink?
-喝
-那我请你喝一杯
-Yeah . -Then I'II buy you a drink.
好的
Okay.
你的裙子破了
Hey, honey, your skirt's spIit there.
-你喝什么？
-威士忌
-What do you drink, kid? -Bourbon .
威士忌？
Bourbon?
-要加冰吗？
-不，加水行了
-On the rocks? -Yeah . No. With water.
你想先加冰吗？
AII right, you want rocks first, though , don't you?
-好的
-没问题
-Yeah . -Good , you got them .
-不要太多
-给你的，可使你自由自在
-Not too much . -AII right. That'II set you free.
-跟她相识已久吗？
-不太久，我住在楼上
-You know the kid Iong? -Not very. I Iive upstairs.
说笑吗？看看这儿
You're kidding . Boy, Iook at this pIace, wiII you?
难以置信，像个废墟
What a pIace. It's unbeIievabIe. What a dump.
你认为怎样？
What do you think?
-什么怎样？
-她是不是？
-About what? -Is she or isn't she?
等等
Wait a minute. HoId it.
-哈瑞特
-J.B.你好
-Harriet. -H i , J . B.
J.B.？奥杰，怎么了？
"J . B."? O.J . What is that?
你好
AII right. HeIIo there.
-他是吉尔
-你好
-You know GiI . -Yeah . How are you? Good to see you .
-喝一杯如何？
-厨房…
-How about a drink? -Fine. In the kitchen .
-有你需要的一切
-谢谢
-You'II find everything you need . -Thanks.
甜心，是你
So. . . Oh , honey, that is you , that is you .
佛烈，很高兴你来了
Fred , darIing , I'm so gIad you couId come.
我买来乔迁礼物
I brought you a house present, something for the bookcase.
你真好
You're sweet.
九条生命
很好看吗？奥杰，给我香烟
Doesn't that Iook nice? Give me a cigarette, O.J .
没问题
Sure, sure.
我的经纪人奥杰广交朋友
O.J . 's a great agent. He knows a terrific Iot of phone numbers.
杰瑞沃德的电话号码是几号？
What's Jerry WaId's phone number, O.J . ?
我已下班
Oh , come on , Iay off.
我想你致电告诉他，佛烈是一名天才
DarIing , I want you to caII him and teII him what a genius Fred is.
我来
Yeah , I got it.
别害羞，你不是自夸，我说你是天才
Stop bIushing , Fred . You didn't say you were genius, I did .
别推辞，你怎样使佛烈…
So quit staIIing , O.J . Just teII me what you're going to do
名成利就？
to make Fred rich and famous.
你何不让佛烈解决这事？
Now why don't you Iet Fred baby and me settIe that matter, huh , puppy?
记着，我是经纪人
Okay. But just remember, I'm the agent.
他已经有一名设计师。我是经纪人。
He's aIready got a decorator, I'm the agent.
等等
HoId it. HoId it.
你们好，进来吧
H i , there, boys. Come on in , there.
厨房有一切必需品
Right in the kitchen , you'II find everything you need .
听着，佛烈
So, Iisten , Fred baby.
-不，我叫保罗
-我还以为你叫佛烈
-No, it's PauI baby. -Oh , it is? I thought it was Fred baby.
-不
-你还没回答我的问题
-No. -WeII , answer the question , aII right?
-她是不是？
-是不是什么？
-Is she or isn't she? -Is she or isn't she what?
骗子
A phoney.
我不知道，看来不是
I don't know. I don't think so.
看来不是？你错了，她是
You don't think so, huh? WeII , you're wrong , she is.
但另一方面你说对了，因为她是真正的骗子。
But on the other hand , you're right, because she's a reaI phoney.
因为她真的相信…
You know why? Because she honestIy beIieves aII this phoney junk
自己所干的事
that she beIieves in .
我是说真的，我喜欢她，真的
I mean it. Now Iook, I Iike the kid . I mean , I sincereIy Iike the kid . I do.
我很敏感
I mean , I'm sensitive, that's why.
你要敏感才会喜欢她
I mean , you gotta be sensitive to Iike the kid , you know what I mean?
这是一种感觉，很诗意
It's what you caII a touch , a streak of the poet,
你懂吗？
you know what I mean?
你跟她相识很久吗？
You known her Iong?
我发掘她
Are you kidding? I'm the guy that discovered her.
我是奥杰伯曼
I'm O.J . Berman .
数年前…
A coupIe of years ago, back on the coast there.
她只是一个小孩。她别具风格，气质不凡
She was just a kid . Of course, she had a Iot of styIe. A Iot of cIass.
-什么不凡？
-气质不凡
-A Iot of what? -CIass. I said she had Iot of cIass.
但当她开口说话
But of course, when she opened her mouth ,
你就知道她是乡下人
you didn't know what she was taIking , whether she was a hiIIbiIIy or an Okie.
你知道替她改掉口音花了多少时间？
You know how Iong it took me to smooth out that accent?
-不知
-我告诉你多久
-No. -I'II teII you how Iong .
一年，可知我怎样做到？
One year. You know how we did it?
我们要她学法文
We gave her French Iessons. Yeah .
当她学懂法文
Figured once she couId imitate French ,
学习英语就不是难题
she'd have no troubIe imitating EngIish .
最终我为她安排了试镜
And , finaIIy, when I thought she'd be ready, I arranged for a IittIe screen test.
试镜前一夜，我差点气死了
WeII , the night before the screen test. . . WeII , I couId've kiIIed myseIf.
试镜前一夜，电话响起
The night before the screen test, the phone rings.
我接起电话，她说： “我是荷莉”
I pick it up, I said , "O.J . speaking ." She says, "This is HoIIy."
我说： “你看来在远处”
I says, "HoIIy? HoIIy, you sound so far away, honey. What's with you?"
她说她在纽约
She says, "I'm in New York."
我说： “但你明天要去试镜”
I said , "What? You got a screen test tomorrow."
她说不曾到过纽约
She says, "I'm in New York because I've never been to New York before."
我叫她回来
I said , "Get yourseIf on the pIane. Get back here."
但她说不想
She says, "I don't wanna."
我说： “你不想回来是什么意思？”
I say, "What do you mean , you don't wanna? What do you want?"
她说不想，我说： “你想怎样？”
She says, "I don't wanna." I say, "What do you want?"
她说： “我知道后再通知你”
She says, "When I find out what I want, I'm gonna Iet you know." Bang .
-所以佛烈，你别对我说…
-我是保罗
-So, Iook, Fred baby, you know. . . -It's PauI baby.
别说她不是骗子
PauI baby. Sure. I mean , don't teII me that she isn't a phoney.
你懂吗？
You know what I mean?
亲爱的甜心，你去了哪儿？
Irving . Honey, Irving , where have you been?
很好，谢谢
Great, thanks.
麦克，我想找你
Mike, darIing , I tried reaching you aII day Iong .
但你的留言机坏了
Your answering service doesn't answer.
你知道留言机问题很多
You know the troubIe peopIe have with answering services.
我也是这么想，你妈从没…
WeII , I guess so. CarefuI your mother never. . .
她很精神
She's been running around .
你看来很好
You Iook so wonderfuI .
我知道，他也知道她说了他的事
I know. And after aII that she said about him , and he knows that.
荷莉
HoIIy.
-时间
-什么？
-Time, darIing . -What?
现在几点？
The time?
-你有手表吗？
-不，我没有
-Do you have a watch? -No, I don't.
-让我看，现在六时四十五分
-谢谢你
-Let me see it. It's 6:45. -Thank you so much , dear.
可以借我吗？
Can I borrow it?
真的有需要吗？
ReaIIy, was that necessary?
派对很热闹，他们是谁？
This is some party. Who are aII these peopIe, anyhow?
不知道，人们自动涌来
Who knows? The word gets out.
你不介意吗？
You don't mind , do you , darIing?
补给来了
Reinforcements.
-我该放在哪儿？
-那儿
-Where do I put it? -Right in there.
荷莉
HoIIy.
HoIIy, darIing .
-怎么了？
-梅格怀尔伍德
-What's that? -Mag WiIdwood .
她是模特儿，并且是闷蛋
She's a modeI , beIieve it or not, and a thumping bore.
看看她带来的好东西
But just Iook at the goodies she brought with her.
他也不错。若你喜欢肤色黝黑、英俊的富商，
He's aII right, I suppose, if you Iike dark, handsome, rich-Iooking men
加上热情和牙齿齐全
with passionate natures and too many teeth .
我不是指这个，是另一个
I don't mean that one. I mean the other one.
-另一个？
-他是拉斯蒂特拉勒
-The other one? -He's Rusty TrawIer.
拉斯蒂特拉勒
Rusty TrawIer.
他是美国第九富商，未到五十岁
He happens to be the ninth-richest man in America under 50.
这是非常有用的资料
Now that indeed is a remarkabIe piece of information to have at your fingertips.
我很留意这些消息
I keep track of these things.
-抱歉，你欠我四十七…
-替我拿着好吗？
-Excuse me. You owe me $47. . . -HoId this a minute, wiII you , darIing?
你在这儿干什么？
Mag , darIing , what are you doing here?
我在上面和雄志工作
Honey, I was upstairs working with Yunioshi .
为《哈泼时尚》拍摄复活节特刊
Easter stuff for the Bazaar.
接着他们俩来接我
Then these two nice boys came to pick me up.
其实消息传达错误
It was a mistake, of course. My wires got crossed somewhere.
但他们均非常可爱
They were both very sweet about it.
他是来自巴西的…
May I present Jos茅 da SiIva Pereira?
荷西贝雷拉
He's from BraziI .
戈莱利小姐
Miss GoIightIy.
你真好，让我参加你的派对
Very kind of you , Miss GoIightIy, to aIIow me to attend your party.
我对北美文化很有兴趣
I'm so interested in North American cuIture.
我曾到自由女神像
I've been aIready, of course, to the Statue of Liberty
和那著名餐馆
and to the restaurant Automatique.
这是我首次到访北美民居
But this is the first time I'm in a typicaI North American home.
他是不是很棒？
WouIdn't he just meIt in your mouth?
这是拉斯蒂特拉勒
And this is Mr Rusty TrawIer.
她是戈莱利小姐
Miss GoIightIy.
我带他们来你不会生气吧？
You're not vexed at me for bringing them?
-当然不会
-我很高兴
-Of course not, darIing . -I'm gIad .
谁会给我美国威士忌？
Now, who's going to bring me a bourbon?
-奥杰
-什么事？
-O.J . -Yeah?
-你可替怀尔伍德小姐拿饮品吗？
-谁是怀尔伍德小姐？
-WouId you get Miss WiIdwood a drink? -Yeah . Which one's Miss WiIdwood?
伯曼先生，我们还没正式介绍
Mr Berman , we haven't been formaIIy introduced ,
我是梅格怀尔伍德，来自山脉连连的…
but I'm Mag WiIdwood from WiIdwood , Arkansas.
阿肯色州
That's hiII country.
视这儿为家吧
You just make yourseIf right at home, senhor.
别烦恼
Oh , do not troubIe yourseIf.
我想学习贵国的风俗习惯
I'm contented to stand observing the customs of your country.
好的
Okay, you do that.
跟我来，特拉勒先生
Now, come aIong , Mr TrawIer.
看看有什么可使你惊喜
Let's see what we can find to amuse you with .
噢，不
Oh , no.
不，不，不
No, no, no.
我不该来接你
I wasn't supposed to pick you up.
你是要来接我，但最后我叫吉尔来
You said you wouId pick me up, and at the Iast minute, I had GiI come. . .
我不该来
Look, I wasn't supposed to pick you up, here or anywhere.
-是
-戈莱利小姐
-Yes? -Miss GoIightIy?
我警告你
This time I'm warning you .
这次我一定会找警察
I am definiteIy this time going to caIIing the poIice !
晚安
Good evening .
有重要事吗？
Is it something important?
不，只是住在楼上的人
No. Just the guy upstairs.
他投诉太嘈吵
CompIaining about the noise.
他很愤怒吗？
He's angry.
他提及要去报警
WeII , he did mention something about caIIing the poIice.
警员？
Oh , the poIice. The poIice?
我不能碰上他们，我最好找怀尔伍德小姐并且离去
Oh . That I cannot have. I'd better Iook for Miss WiIdwood and go.
我的情郎…
To think I'd find a beau of mine,
追求一名好莱坞劣货
mousing after a piece of cheap HoIIywood trash .
-梅格，你是一名闷蛋
-闭嘴
-Mag , darIing , you're being a bore. -Shut up.
你知道会发生何事吗？
You . You know what's going to happen to you?
我会带你到动物园，让牦牛吃掉你
I am going to march you over to the zoo and feed you to the yak.
只要我喝完这杯就行
Just as soon as I finish this drink.
避开
Timber!
抱歉
Sorry.
艾德，晚安
Good evening , Ed .
-他是保罗
-对
-It's PauI baby. -Oh , yes.
-你记得艾文吗？
-你好
-You remember Irving , don't you? -Yeah . H i , Irving .
-他是荷西
-很高兴和你碰面
-This is Jos茅. -N ice to meet you , Jos茅.
-幸会
-是
-WonderfuI seeing you . -Yes.
珠宝贼人
JeweI thieves.
星星
沙里帮我理财
SaIIy heIps me with my accounts.
我对数字毫无认识
I have no head for figures at aII .
我努力尝试储钱
I'm trying desperateIy to save some money. You know, I toId you .
但总不成功
I just can't seem to.
他要我记下一切
He makes me write down everything in there.
我买了什么，花费多少
What I get, what I spend .
我以往有支票户口，他迫我取消了
I used to have a checking account, but he made me get rid of that.
他认为我用现金更实际
He feeIs, for me, anyway, that it's better to operate on a cash basis, tax-wise.
佛烈，某天你将这书变成小说
Some day, Mr Fred , you take this book, turn it into a noveI .
一切都在内，只需加一些细节
Everything is there. Just fiII in a IittIe of the detaiIs.
一定惹笑
CertainIy wouId be good for some Iaughs.
看来不是
No. No, I don't think so.
这本书会使人心伤
This is a book wouId break the heart.
“菲兹西蒙斯先生，女厕，五十元”
"Mr Fitzsimmons, powder room , $50."
“修补黑色裙子”
"Less $ 1 8."
“灭去十八元”
"Repair one bIack satin dress."
“猫粮，二十七角”
"Cat food , 27 cents."
沙里，停止，你使我脸红了
SaIIy, darIing , pIease stop. You're making me bIush .
但你对菲兹西蒙斯的说法没错
他是鼠辈
But you're right about Jack Fitzsimmons, he's an absoIute rat.
当然，我只认识鼠辈
I guess, of course, I don't reaIIy know anybody but rats.
当然，除了佛烈
Except, of course, Fred here.
你认为佛烈是好人吗？
You do think Fred is nice, don't you , SaIIy?
对你来说，我希望他是好人
For you , I hope he is.
跟我吻别
Give me a kiss goodbye.
沙里叔叔，下周再见
Goodbye, U ncIe SaIIy. TiII next week.
沙里叔叔，再见
Goodbye, U ncIe SaIIy.
别忘记寄那本书来
Goodbye and don't forget to send that book, eh?
不会忘
I won't.
天气报告怎样？
What about the weather report?
对
Oh , yes.
新奥尔良本周将下雪
Snow fIurries expected this weekend in New OrIeans.
新奥尔良本周将下雪？
Snow fIurries expected this weekend in New OrIeans?
真奇怪
Isn't that just the weirdest?
数百万年来，新奥尔良也不曾下雪
I bet they haven't had snow in New OrIeans for a miIIion years.
我不知道他怎么想出来
I don't know how he thinks them up.
我的朋友
有一位很可爱、胆小的女孩
她独居，养了一只无名的猫
月河
Moon River
宽广
Wider than a mile
我遇上你
l'm crossing you in style
某天
Some day
造梦者
Oh, dream maker
你使人心碎
You heartbreaker
不论你去哪儿
Wherever you're going
我也跟着走
l'm going your way
两名漂泊者
Two drifters
去看外面的世界
Off to see the world
外面的天地
There's such a lot of world
多姿多采
To see
我们
We're after
在同一
The same
彩虹下
Rainbow's end
在那儿静候
Waiting 'round the bend
我的朋友
My huckleberry friend
月河
Moon River
跟我
And me
-你好
-H i . -H i .
-你在干什么？
-写作
-What you doing? -Writing .
很好
Good .
你好
WeII , heIIo.
-怎么了？
-我不知道
-What's wrong? -I don't know.
可能没什么的
It's probabIy nothing .
我想看看他是否仍在
I want to see if he's stiII there.
看看谁仍在？你在说什么？
See if who's stiII there? What are you taIking about?
看
Look.
昨天下午我已留意到他
See? I noticed him yesterday afternoon .
我不想过分敏感，但…
I didn't say anything , I didn't want to sound neurotic
-今天他又在此
-你认为他是谁？
-but when he's there again today. . . -Who do you think he is?
可能是任何人，但我认为…
It couId be anybody, of course, but what crossed my mind was
比尔派他来监视我们？
suppose BiII's having us watched , huh?
好的，我会处理这事
Okay, I'II take care of this.
不要去，求求你
No. No, don't. PIease.
若这是事实，你会坏事
Look, if that's what it is, you'II onIy make everything worse.
我会小心行事，你在这儿等候
I'II be carefuI . You wait here.
请你不要去
DarIing , pIease don't. I don't think you shouId .
别担心
Now take it easy.
我只想查明这事
I just want to find out what this is aII about.
好的，你想怎样？
AII right, what do you want?
孩子，我需要朋友
Son , I need a friend .
这是我，那个是她
That's me. That's her.
那是他弟弟佛烈
That's her brother Fred .
你是荷莉的父亲？
You're HoIIy's father?
她不是叫荷莉
Her name ain't HoIIy.
她叫露拉美巴恩斯
She was LuIa Mae Barnes.
她是我妻子
Was tiII she married me.
我是戈莱利医生
I'm her husband , Doc GoIightIy.
保罗华杰
PauI Varjak.
我医治马匹，我是兽医
I'm a horse doctor. AnimaI man .
也在德州附近务农
Do some farming , too, near TuIip, Texas.
她的弟弟佛烈，很快离开军队
Her brother Fred's getting out of the army soon .
露拉美该和丈夫…
LuIa Mae beIongs home with her husband ,
弟弟、儿女在一起
her brother and her chiIdren .
儿女？
ChiIdren?
他们是她的儿女
Them's her chiIdren .
她有四名子女？
She's got four chiIdren?
我不是指她亲生的
Now, son , I didn't cIaim they was her naturaI-born chiIdren .
他们珍贵的母亲，是难得的女性
Their own precious mother, precious woman
她在1955年7月4日独立纪念日那天去世
passed away J uIy the 4th , Independence Day, 1 955,
灾难的一年
the year of the drought.
我和露拉美结婚时，她快要十四岁
When I married LuIa Mae, she was going on 1 4.
你以为十四岁的人不太清楚…
Now, you might think the average person going on 1 4
自己的想法
wouIdn't know his own mind .
但露拉美…
But you take LuIa Mae.
与别人不同
She was an exceptionaI person .
我跟你说
I'II teII you , son ,
她离去使我们心碎
she just pIumb broke our hearts when she run off Iike she done.
她毫无原因出走
Just pIain had no reason .
所有家务均由她的女儿负责
AII the housework was done by her daughters.
露拉美就这样离开了
LuIa Mae couId just take it easy.
她那时很胖
I teII you , that woman got positiveIy fat
弟弟则像个巨人
whiIe her brother, he growed up into a giant.
跟他们到来时有点分别
Which is a sight different from the way they come to us.
他们以往是野孩子
A coupIe of wiId young'uns, they was.
我发现他们在屋外偷奶和火鸡蛋
I caught them outside the house steaIing miIk and turkey eggs.
他们跟无良的人…
LuIa Mae and her brother had been Iiving
住在图纳
with some mean , no-account peopIe about 1 00 miIe east of TuIip.
她离开那儿是有理由的
She had good cause to run off from that house.
离开我家却毫无理由
Never had none to Ieave mine.
她的弟弟有离开吗？
What about her brother? Didn't he Ieave, too?
没有，佛烈跟我们一起，直至去参军
No, sir. We had Fred with us tiII they took him in the army.
佛烈来了一封信，所以我想跟她谈谈
That's what I come to taIk to her about. I had a Ietter from him .
他在二月就离开军队
He's getting out of the army in February.
所以我来找她
That's why I got on a Greyhound bus to come to get her.
她该和丈夫、子女、弟弟一起
LuIa Mae's pIace is with her husband , her chiIdren , and her brother.
什么？
H uh?
这是吃爆米花得来的奖品
你想要吗？
It's the prize in the Cracker Jack. You want it?
我永不明白她为何要离开
Never couId understand why that woman run off.
别告诉我她不快乐
Don't teII me she weren't happy.
她说话滔滔不绝
TaIky as a jaybird she was.
什么也爱谈
With something smart to say on every subject.
说话较广播还多
Better than the radio.
求婚当晚我哭得像宝宝
The night I proposed , I cried Iike a baby.
她说： “你为何哭？我们定会结婚
She said , "What you want to cry for, Doc? Of course we'II be married .
“以往我不曾结婚”
"I've never been married before."
我拥抱着她大笑
WeII , I had to Iaugh and to hug and to squeeze her.
“不曾结婚”
"Never been married before."
我给你忠告，我需要朋友
Listen , son . I advised you I need a friend .
因为我不想吓怕她
'Cause I don't want to surprise or scare her none.
做我的朋友，告诉她我来了
Be my friend . Let her know I'm here.
你愿意帮我吗？
WiII you do that for me, son?
当然，若你想这样
Yeah , sure, Doc. If that's what you want.
来吧
Come on .
好
AII right.
来了
Coming .
我要外出
Oh , darIing , I'm just on my way out.
我该在半小时前到《二十一》
I was supposed to be at 2 1 haIf an hour ago.
或许我们明天再喝酒吧？
Maybe we can have a drink or something tomorrow, huh?
好的，露拉美
Sure, LuIa Mae,
若明天你还在
if you're stiII here tomorrow.
求求你，他在哪儿？
Oh , pIease, where is he?
佛烈？
Fred?
天啊
Gosh .
露拉美
LuIa Mae.
你没吃东西吗？你太瘦了
Gee, honey, don't they feed you up here? You're so skinny.
-你好，医生
-露拉美
-H i , Doc. -Gosh , LuIa Mae.
我来了
Kingdom come.
怎么了？你没事吗？
What is it? What's the matter? Are you aII right?
没事吧
I guess so. No, I'm not.
-佛烈，你可以帮我吗？
-若我可以的话
-Fred , wiII you heIp me? -If I can .
我想你陪我们在车站
I want you to come to the bus station with us, Doc and me.
-什么？
-他还以为我会跟他回去
-What? -He stiII thinks I'm going back with him .
我需要人支持，我不能独自面对
I need support. I don't think I can pIay this scene aIone.
我该怎办？他是你的丈夫
HoIIy, what can I do? He's your husband .
-不，他不是
-他不是？
-No, he's not. -He's not?
多年前已解除婚约，但他不死心
It was annuIIed ages ago, but he just won't accept it.
求求你，我会说你来看我们
PIease, Fred . I'II teII him you're coming to see us off.
别说话
Don't say anything .
一小时后在门前等我们
Just meet us out front in about an hour. PIease?
你在这儿等候，我去拿手袋
You wait right here, honey. I'II get the bag .
我想去买杂志
Why don't I get some magazines?
佛烈，求你别离开我
PIease, Fred . Don't Ieave me.
注意
Attention, please.
到达拉斯…
Leaving from platform five, through coach to Dallas,
费城、哥伦布、印第安诺波利斯、特雷霍特…
Philadelphia, Columbus, lndianapolis, Terre Haute,
圣路易、土耳沙、俄克拉荷马市、丹尼森、达拉斯…
St. Louis, Tulsa, Oklahoma City, Denison, Dallas.
露拉美，我们要起行了
Come on , LuIa Mae. That's us.
医生，我不会跟你走
Doc, I'm not coming with you .
我们慢慢走，我尝试作出解释
Come on . Let's waIk together quietIy and I'II try and heIp you understand .
佛烈，帮我向他解释
HeIp me taIk to him , Fred .
没关系
It's aII right, son .
我很感激你想帮忙，但这是我和露拉美之间的事
I appreciate you wanna heIp, but it's between LuIa Mae and me.
当然
Sure, Doc.
露拉美，我爱你
I Iove you , LuIa Mae.
我知道，这就是烦恼所在
I know you do, and that's just the troubIe.
你爱上野性的东西是错误
It's a mistake you aIways made, Doc, trying to Iove a wiId thing .
你经常带野生动物回家
You were aIways Iugging home wiId things.
一次是折翼的鹰
Once it was a hawk with a broken wing
另一次是断脚的成年野猫
and another time it was a fuII-grown wiIdcat with a broken Ieg .
记得吗？
Remember?
露拉美，有时候…
LuIa Mae, there's something . . .
你不应爱上野性的东西
You mustn't give your heart to a wiId thing .
你越爱它，它变得越强
The more you do, the stronger they get.
直至它离开，跑到树林或飞到树上
U ntiI they're strong enough to run into the woods or fIy into a tree.
再去更高的树，直达天际
And then to a higher tree and then to the sky.
露拉美，我定要告诉你一件事
LuIa Mae, there's something I got to teII you .
数周前我收到佛烈的一封信
A coupIe of weeks ago, I got a Ietter from young Fred .
他很好吗？
From Fred? He's aII right, isn't he?
他很好
Yeah , he's fine, I guess.
二月他会离开军队
He's getting out of the army in February.
-他信里是这么说的
-二月？
-That's what he wrote to teII me. -In February?
只相距四个月
WeII , that's onIy four months.
明白吗？你必须跟我回去
So you see, you got to come back with me, LuIa Mae.
你该和我、子女及弟弟一起
Your pIace is with me and your chiIdren and your brother.
医生，你得明白我不可回头
Doc, you've got to understand . I can't come back.
你得明白我所说的话
And you got to understand what I'm trying to teII you .
我不想给你压力，但必须这样
Now, I don't want to seem Iike I'm pressuring you none, but now I got to.
你不回来…
If you don't come back with me,
我就要写信告诉佛烈…
I'm gonna have to write young Fred and teII him that
他要另找家园或继续参军
unIess he wants to Iook out for hisseIf, he better sign up for another hitch .
别这样做，别写信给他
Doc, don't you do that. Don't write that to him .
我会自己写信给他，我要他跟我在一起。
I'II write him myseIf and teII him I want him here with me.
别担心，我会照顾他
I'II take care of him . Don't you worry.
露拉美，你是痴人说梦
You're taIking crazy, LuIa Mae.
住口，我不再是露拉美
Doc, stop caIIing me that. I'm not LuIa Mae any more.
好的，露拉美
AII right, LuIa Mae.
你该知道自己在干什么
I guess you know what you're doing .
你替我看着她好吗？
Keep an eye on her, wiII you , son?
至少确保她吃点东西
At Ieast see she eats something once in a whiIe.
好的
Sure, Doc.
她太瘦了
So skinny.
医生，求你谅解我
PIease, Doc. PIease understand .
我爱你，但我不再是露拉美
I Iove you , but I'm just not LuIa Mae any more.
不再是
I'm not.
你可知道什么最可怕？
You know the terribIe thing , Fred , darIing?
我仍然是露拉美
I am stiII LuIa Mae.
那个十四岁，偷火鸡蛋越过荆棘的女孩
Fourteen years oId , steaIing turkey eggs and running through a briar patch .
除了现在我将之称为令人满面通红的事
But now I caII it having the mean reds.
现在去蒂芙尼太早了
WeII , it's stiII too earIy to go to Tiffany's.
最好是去喝酒
I guess the next best thing is a drink.
对，我很需要喝酒
Yes, I very much need a drink.
-佛烈，你愿意请我喝酒吗？
-当然
-WiII you buy me one, Fred , darIing? -Sure.
答应我一件事，我喝醉了才送我回家
OnIy promise me one thing . Don't take me home untiI I'm drunk.
该是非常醉才对
U ntiI I'm very drunk indeed .
你认为她有才华吗？
Do you think she's taIented?
-她有深度吗？
-不
-DeepIy and importantIy taIented? -No.
只是很肤浅
AmusingIy and superficiaIIy taIented , yes,
但谈不上有深度
but deepIy and importantIy, no.
很优美
Gracious.
你认为她收入丰富吗？
Do you think she's handsomeIy paid?
丰富
Oh , indeed .
让我告诉你
WeII , Iet me teII you something , mister.
若我的收入像她那么丰富，我定会较她富有
If I had her money, I'd be richer than she is.
-你怎知道？
-因为我有糖果店
-How do you figure that? -Because I'd keep the candy store.
沙里托马图就是我的糖果店
OId SaIIy Tomato. That's my candy store.
我总有沙里
I'd aIways keep SaIIy.
所以我较她富有
And that's why I'd be richer than she is.
我们要更多空气
We'd better get a IittIe more air.
汤姆、狄克和哈利，更正
. . .Tom , Dick, and Harry. No. Correction .
该是汤姆、狄克和席德。哈利是他的朋友
Every Tom , Dick and Sid , Harry was his friend .
汤姆、狄克和席德糟透了，他们以为带女孩去吃饭…
Anyway, every Tom , Dick and Sid thinks that if he takes a girI to dinner,
她就会像小猫般依偎着他们
she'II just curI up Iike a kitten in a IittIe furry baII at his feet, right?
我曾跟他们吃饭
I have by actuaI count been taken to dinner
两个月来跟二十六个不同的鼠辈一起
by 26 different rats in the Iast two months.
若包括超级鼠辈班尼谢克立…
Twenty-seven , if you count Benny ShackIett,
就是二十七人
who is in many ways a super-rat.
-我忘了带钥匙
-没问题，我刚按铃了
-I think I forgot my key. -Never mind . I just buzzed Yunioshi .
你想知道有趣的事吗？
Do you wanna know something funny?
大部分的鼠辈都会…
In spite of the fact that most of these rats fork up
给我五十元作为去女厕的费用
$50 for the powder room Iike IittIe doIIs,
我的银行户口较半年前…
I find I have again by actuaI count $9 Iess in the oId bank account
少了九元
than I had six months ago.
佛烈
So, my darIing Fred ,
今天我作了重大决定
I have tonight made a very serious decision .
什么决定？
And what is that?
我不再干这事了
No Ionger wiII I pIay the fieId .
-恭喜你
-这一行…
-CongratuIations. -The fieId stinks,
糟透了
both economicaIIy and sociaIIy.
我要放弃
And I'm giving it up.
戈莱利小姐，这次我不只通知警察…
Miss GoIightIy, this time I'm not onIy caIIing the poIice,
更通知消防局、纽约州房屋局
but the fire department and the New York State Housing Commission ,
有需要的话会找卫生局
and , if necessary, the Board of HeaIth !
静下来，你想吵醒所有人吗？
Quiet up there. You want to wake the whoIe house?
戈莱利小姐被无礼打扰前想说…
As Miss GoIightIy was saying before she was so rudeIy interrupted ,
戈莱利小姐作出宣布
Miss GoIightIy further announces her intention
她会全力以赴
to devote her many considerabIe taIents
务求可以尽快嫁给…
to the immediate capture, for the purpose of matrimony
拉瑟福德先生
of Mr Rutherford .
朋友称呼他拉斯蒂，我肯定他有很多朋友
Rusty to his friends, of whom I'm sure he has many.
-特拉勒
-谁？
-TrawIer. -Who?
拉斯蒂特拉勒，数周前你曾在派对见过他
Rusty TrawIer. You met him at my party a coupIe of weeks ago.
和梅格怀尔伍德一起来
He came with Mag WiIdwood .
不是英俊的拉丁人
Not the beautifuI Latin type.
另一人，外表像猪的那一位
The other one, the one that Iooks Iike a pig .
记得吗？
Remember?
不到五十岁的美国第九富商？
The ninth-richest man in America under 50?
你像是看不起我
Do I detect a Iook of disapprovaI in your eye?
要嫁给他是困难的
Tough beans, buddy, 'cause that's the way it's gonna be.
你好，猫咪
H i , cat.
荷莉，你醉了
HoIIy, you're drunk.
对
True.
-非常对，但没所谓
-你在干什么？
-AbsoIuteIy true. True, but irreIevant. -What are you doing?
你该和…
So I think we shouId have a drink
新任拉斯蒂太太喝酒
to the new Mrs Rusty TrawIer.
-就是我
-慢慢来
-Me. -Hey, take it easy.
怎么了？你认为我办不到吗？
What's the matter, don't you think I can do it?
我是认真想知道，你真的认为我不行吗？
TeII me. SeriousIy, I'm interested . Don't you think I can?
你也听到医生的话
You heard the Doc.
弟弟服完兵役后…
My brother gets out of the army in February
医生不愿收留他，一切全依赖我
and the Doc won't take him back. So it's aII up to me.
你为何不明白
I don't know why you don't understand .
我需要钱，我会用尽方法赚钱
I need money, and I'II do whatever I have to do to get it.
所以…
So,
下个月我就是拉斯蒂太太
this time next month , I'II be the new Mrs Rusty TrawIer.
我们应该为此而喝酒
And I think we shouId have a IittIe drink to that.
没有酒了，真扫兴
It's aII gone. Isn't that too bad?
楼上有威士忌吗？
Got any whisky upstairs?
-你喝够了
-去拿威士忌吧
-But you've had enough . -Go ahead . Get the whisky.
我愿意付款
I'II pay you for it.
-荷莉，求求你
-你看不起我
-HoIIy, pIease. -No, no, you disapprove of me
我不用看不起我的人请我喝酒
and I do not accept drinks from gentIemen who disapprove of me.
别忘了，我可付钱去买
I'II pay for my own whisky and don't you forget it.
荷莉
HoIIy.
看不起我的人不用请我喝酒
I do not accept drinks from disapproving gentIemen .
尤其是他是由女人所供养
EspeciaIIy not disapproving gentIemen who are kept by other Iadies.
拿去吧
So take it.
你应惯于使用女人所赚的钱
You shouId be used to taking money from Iadies by now.
我是你，就会小心金钱
If I were you , I'd be more carefuI with my money.
从拉斯蒂身上赚钱不容易
Rusty TrawIer is too hard a way of earning it.
你从这儿走出门口不用四秒
It shouId take you exactIy four seconds to cross from here to that door.
我给你两秒
I'II give you two.
城市信托银行-保罗华杰      五十元整
拉斯蒂特拉勒结婚
花花公子女继承人说： “够了”
你好
H i .
我来是想谈谈那夜的事
I've come up to taIk to you about the other night,
我看了报纸…
then I saw the paper, and . . .
我感到有点尴尬
WeII , actuaIIy, I'm kind of embarrassed about it,
既然这事与你有关，我想亲自跟你谈
but since it concerns you , I thought I ought to taIk to you about it in person .
什么？
What?
耳塞
The earpIugs.
我不能再经历一次
I can't go through the whoIe thing again .
我是来修好的
It's sufficient to say, I've come to make up.
我还会带来各种消息
And as an added inducement, I have aII kinds of news.
可以进来吗？
Can I come in?
可以，等等，我有穿睡衣吗？
I guess so. Just a minute. Do I have a nightgown on?
没有，你可否转身？
No, I don't. WouId you mind turning around for a second?
算了吧，这句话太过时
Oh , never mind . It's such a corny Iine anyway.
我自己转身好了
I'II turn around myseIf.
进来
Come in .
你看过报纸吗？
Have you seen the paper?
你是指拉斯蒂一事？
Rusty, you mean?
我已知道了
Yes. I know aII about it.
我看错了他，对吗？
CertainIy had him pegged wrong , didn't I?
我以为他是鼠辈，其实他是超级鼠辈
I thought he was just a rat, but he was a super-rat aII aIong .
穿着老鼠衣服的超级鼠辈
A super-rat in rat's cIothing .
你还没知道最精彩部分
You don't even know the best part.
他不只是鼠辈或超级鼠辈
Not onIy was he a rat, or a super-rat, rather,
他已经破产了
he was aIso broke.
破产，但不是一毛钱也没有
Broke. I mean , but not a farthing .
他的家人有钱，但他本人已破产
H is famiIy has money, of course, but he personaIIy is broke.
他欠债七十万元
It turns out he owes $700, 000.
试想想一人欠债七十万元
Can you imagine anyone owing $700, 000?
四十三元，对
$43, yes.
无论如何，他因此娶那丑女皇
Anyway, that's why he decided to marry the queen of the pig peopIe.
佛烈，我告诉你一件事
I'II teII you one thing , Fred , darIing ,
为了钱，我会立刻跟你结婚
I'd marry you for your money in a minute.
-你会为钱跟我结婚吗？
-马上会
-WouId you marry me for my money? -In a minute.
幸好我们均不是有钱人
So I guess it's pretty Iucky neither of us is rich , huh?
是
Yeah .
佛烈，很高兴见到你
Fred , darIing , I'm so gIad to see you .
你近来怎样？
What have you been doing?
主要在写作
Writing , mostIy.
我卖出一个故事，今早刚获悉
SoId a story. Just got word this morning .
真美妙
Oh , that's marveIIous. It reaIIy is.
但…
But. . .
你的设计师有何看法？
OnIy how does your decorator friend feeI about it?
你不是要自救吗？
I thought you were supposed to be saving yourseIf and aII of that?
你可知道？
You know something?
我还没告诉她
I haven't got around to teIIing her about it yet.
我们何不出外…
Look, why don't we go out and have a drink
庆祝一番？
or take a waIk or something to ceIebrate?
好的
AII right.
冰箱子里好像有香槟
I think there's some champagne in the icebox.
我换裙子时你替我开了它
Why don't you open it whiIe I get dressed?
好
Okay.
以往我不曾在吃早餐前喝香槟
I don't think I've ever drunk champagne before breakfast before.
曾数度吃早餐时喝香槟
With breakfast on severaI occasions.
但不曾在早餐前喝
But never before, before.
我有一个好点子
Now I've got a wonderfuI idea.
我们可做一些以往不曾做的事
We can spend a whoIe day doing things we've never done before.
首先由你开始，接着是我
We'II take turns. First something you've never done, then me.
当然，很难想到有什么是我没做过的
Of course, I can't reaIIy think of anything I've never done.
我不曾在早上散步
I've never been for a waIk in the morning before.
来了纽约后不曾试过
At Ieast not since I've been in New York.
六时我曾在第五大街散步
I've waIked up Fifth Avenue at 6: 00,
但那是晚上
but as far as I'm concerned , that's stiII night.
-那算是吗？
-当然，现在我们平手了
-Do you think it counts? -Sure it counts. Now we're even .
-你不喜欢吗？
-喜欢什么？
-Don't you just Iove it? -Love what?
蒂芙尼
Tiffany's.
不是很美妙吗？
Isn't it wonderfuI?
这儿不会有坏事…
You see what I mean how nothing bad couId ever happen to you
发生
in a pIace Iike this?
我不是蔑视珠宝，钻石除外
It isn't that I give a hoot about jeweIIery, except diamonds, of course.
很特别
Like that.
你认为怎样？
What do you think?
我…
WeII . . .
我认为四十岁前戴钻石很俗气
Of course, personaIIy, I think it wouId be tacky to wear diamonds before I'm 40.
说得对，但目前你该戴些珠宝
WeII , you're right. But in the meantime, you shouId have something .
我会等候
I'II wait.
不，我会买一份礼物给你
No. I'm gonna buy you a present.
你的打字带为我带来好运
You bought me one, a typewriter ribbon , and it brought me Iuck.
但蒂芙尼的东西很贵
AII right, but Tiffany's can be pretty expensive.
我有支票跟十元
I've got my cheque and $ 1 0.
我不会让你花掉支票
Oh , I wouIdn't Iet you cash your cheque.
但我愿意接受低于十元的礼物
But a present for $ 1 0 or under, that I'II accept.
不知蒂芙尼内有什么只值十元
Of course, I don't exactIy know what we're going to find at Tiffany's for $ 1 0.
我可以帮忙吗？
May I heIp you?
或许，我想送这女士一份礼物
Perhaps. ActuaIIy, we were Iooking for a present for the Iady.
好的
CertainIy, sir.
你想送什么类型的礼物？
Is there something speciaI you had in mind?
我们曾考虑钻石
WeII , we had considered diamonds.
我不想冒犯你
Now, I don't want to offend you ,
但这女士认为钻石太低俗
but the Iady feeIs that diamonds are tacky for her.
钻石适合较老的女人
Oh , I think they're divine on oIder women ,
不太适合我
but I don't think they'd be right for me. You do understand?
好
CertainIy.
实不相瞒，还有另一个问题
In aII fairness, I think I ought to expIain . There's aIso a secondary probIem .
经济的问题
One of finance.
我们有消费限额
We can onIy afford to spend a Iimited amount.
-那数目是多少？
-十元
-May I ask how Iimited? -$ 1 0.
十元？
$ 1 0?
这是我们的限额
That was the outside figure, yes.
我明白了
I see.
你们有价值十元的货品吗？
Do you have anything for $ 1 0?
这价钱的货…
WeII , frankIy, madam , within that price range,
种类有限
the variety of merchandise is rather Iimited .
但确有这类货物，让我想想…
However, I do think we might have, Iet me see. . .
这东西新颍小巧
StrictIy as a noveIty, you understand .
这是有钱人士认为珍贵文物
For the Iady and gentIeman who has everything ,
纯银电话自动拨号器
a sterIing siIver teIephone diaIIer
连税价值6.75元
at $6.75, incIuding tax.
纯银电话自动拨号器
A sterIing siIver teIephone diaIIer.
对，连税价值6.75元
Yes, sir. At $6.75, incIuding federaI tax.
价钱合理，但…
WeII , the price is right, but I must say,
我想要一些更…
该怎么说…
I'd rather hoped for something sIightIy more, how shaII I say it,
浪漫的东西
romantic in feeIing .
你认为怎样？
What do you think?
纯银电话自动拨号器不错
As sterIing siIver teIephone diaIIers go,
但你明白我的意思吗？
I certainIy think it's handsome, but, weII , you do understand?
我们已尽力，但…
WeII , we tried , but I guess. . .
你们可有提供刻字服务？
We couId have something engraved , couIdn't we?
有
Yes, I suppose so.
有，确实有
Yes, indeed .
唯一的难题是，你要先在这儿购物
The onIy probIem is, you wouId more or Iess have to buy something first
我们才可替你在物件上刻字
if onIy in order to have some object upon which to pIace the engraving .
难就难在这里
You see the difficuIty.
嗯
WeII . . .
你可在它上面刻字
We couId have this engraved , couIdn't we?
将会很好看的
I think it wouId be very smart.
这该不是蒂芙尼的货物吧？
This, I take it, was not purchased at Tiffany's?
不
No.
它是和…
ActuaIIy, it was purchased concurrent with . . .
事实上…
WeII , actuaIIy, it came inside of. . .
它是吃爆米花的赠品
weII , a box of Cracker Jack.
我明白了
I see.
爆米花内仍有礼物吗？
Do they stiII reaIIy have prizes in Cracker Jack boxes?
-是
-很高兴知道这事
-Oh , yes. -That's nice to know.
给人实在…
It gives one a feeIing of soIidarity,
延续传统的感觉
aImost of continuity with the past, that sort of thing .
蒂芙尼愿意为我们刻字吗？
Do you think Tiffany's wouId reaIIy engrave it for us?
这不会贬低店子的…
I mean , you don't think they wouId feeI it was beneath them
声誉吗？
or anything Iike that?
小姐，这样会打破常规
WeII , it is rather unusuaI , madam .
但本公司非常谅解你们的处境
But I think you'II find that Tiffany's is very understanding .
你说出名字缩写…
If you wouId teII me what initiaIs you wouId Iike,
我们可在明早交货
I think we couId have something ready for you in the morning .
我不是说过这儿好极吗？
Didn't I teII you this was a IoveIy pIace?
这儿是什么地方？
What is this pIace, anyway?
你想坐下，这儿是公共图书馆
You said you wanted to sit down . It's the pubIic Iibrary.
-你不曾来过这儿？
-不，我的第二个新尝试
-You've never been here? -No. That makes two for me.
-我看不见书
-在那儿
-I don't see any books. -They're in there.
看见了吗？
See?
每个抽屉也放满小卡片
Each one of these IittIe drawers is stuffed with IittIe cards.
每张卡写上书名或作者名字
And each IittIe card is a book or an author.
真神奇
I think that's fascinating .
华杰
V-A-R-J-A-K.
真的吗？
ReaIIy?
看，真厉害
Look. Isn't it marveIIous?
找到你了，在公共图书馆里
There you are, right in the pubIic Iibrary.
保罗华杰， 《九条生命》
"Varjak, PauI . Nine Lives. "
还有很多数字
And then a Iot of numbers.
这儿真的有那本书吗？
Do you think they reaIIy have the book itseIf, Iive?
当然，跟我来
Sure. FoIIow me.
57号，是我们
N umber 57. That's us.
57号，保罗华杰的《九条生命》
Fifty-seven , pIease. Nine Lives by Varjak, PauI .
你看过吗？很精彩的
Did you ever read it? It's absoIuteIy marveIIous.
-我不曾看过
-你该看看，是他写的
-No, I'm afraid I haven't. -WeII , you shouId . He wrote it.
他就是保罗华杰
He's Varjak, PauI , in person .
她不相信我
She doesn't beIieve me.
向她展示驾驶执照或信用卡等
Show her your driver's Iicence or Diner's CIub card or something .
他是作者，我向天发誓
Honest, he reaIIy is the author. Cross my heart and kiss my eIbow.
你可以小声一点吗？
WouId you kindIy Iower your voice, miss?
你何不签名留念？
Why don't you autograph it to them?
这不是很好吗？更加有意思
Don't you think it'd be nice? Sort of make it more personaI?
小姐…
ReaIIy, miss. . .
签名吧，别这么自大
Go ahead . Don't be so stuck up, autograph it to them .
好的，我该写上什么？
AII right, what shaII I say?
感性的字句
Something sentimentaI , I think.
你在干什么？
What are you doing? Stop that!
-你在破坏公物
-好的，若你这么认为
-You're defacing pubIic property. -WeII , aII right, if that's the way you feeI .
佛烈，我们走吧
Come on , Fred , darIing . Let's get out of here.
这儿的人不及蒂芙尼的人一半友善
I don't think this pIace is haIf as nice as Tiffany's.
小时候你曾在店里…
Hey, did you ever steaI anything from a five-and-ten
偷东西吗？
when you were a kid , I mean?
不，我是书虫，你呢？
No. I'm the sensitive, bookish type. Did you?
我曾试过，现在偶尔还有偷东西
I used to. I stiII do every now and then , sort of to keep my hand in .
来吧，别畏首畏尾
Come on . Don't be chicken .
现在该由你试试
Anyway, you've never done it, and it's your turn .
我看不见东西
I can't see.
猫咪，你好
H i , cat.
女主人在吗？
Lady of the house at home?
荷莉？
HoIIy?
不请吃就捣蛋
Trick or treat.
你疯了？你知道的，但我也爱你
You're crazy. You know that, don't you? But I Iove you anyway.
-我…
-怎么了？
-2-E. -Yeah?
我要跟你谈谈
I've got to taIk to you .
好的
AII right.
你想喝酒吗？
You want a drink?
我突然觉得…
If this is going to be a serious discussion
若有重要事要谈…
and suddenIy I'm terribIy afraid it is,
你要脱去那滑稽的面具
you're going to have to take off that ridicuIous mask
否则我也戴上面具
or eIse I'm going to have to wear one, too.
求求你
2-E, Iook, pIease.
怎么了？为女孩而烦恼？
What's the matter? GirI troubIe?
是这事吗？
Is that it, darIing?
我明白了
Oh , I see.
不是严重的事
WeII , that's not so serious.
事实上，我也有预感
As a matter of fact, I've been expecting it.
我不能说喜欢发生这事，但我已有心理准备
I can't say I Iike it, but I've been expecting it.
-她是谁？
-此事跟她无关
-Who is she? -Hasn't got anything to do with her.
这是我和你之间的事
This is between you and me.
该是严重的事
Then it is serious.
现在…
WeII , now.
你是很时髦的女孩
2-E, you're a very styIish girI .
我们可否好好了结这事？
Can't we end this styIishIy?
-了结？
-是
-End it? -Yes.
噢
WeII . . .
安迪哈迪找到了爱
I do beIieve Iove has found Andy Hardy.
让我猜猜
Let's see,
女侍应？
a waitress?
售货员？
A saIesgirI?
不，她该是富家女，对吗？
No. She'd have to be someone rich , wouIdn't she, PauI?
一个能帮助你的人
Someone who couId heIp you .
奇怪地…
CuriousIy enough ,
她不能帮助我，更帮不了自己
she's a girI who can't heIp anyone, not even herseIf.
我可以帮助她，这感觉很不错
Thing is, I can heIp her, and it's a nice feeIing for a change.
好的
AII right.
我明白了
I understand .
保罗
I'II teII you what, PauI .
我是一个时髦的女孩
I am a very styIish girI .
-你在干什么？
-写支票
-What are you doing? -Writing a cheque.
别装作惊奇
Don't Iook so bewiIdered .
以往你也见过我写支票
SureIy you've noticed me writing cheques before.
“给保罗华杰一千元”
"Pay to the order of PauI Varjak, $ 1 , 000."
带她出外度假一周
Take her away somewhere for a week.
根据劳工法例
You're entitIed to a vacation with pay.
你可享有有薪假期
SimpIy a matter of fair Iabour practise, darIing .
当然，如果你够聪明…
Of course, if you were reaIIy smart,
你可以集结其男生成立工会
you'd get some of the other boys together and organise a union .
这样你就可得到一切福利
That way you'd get aII the fringe benefits,
例如医疗福利、退休计划…
hospitaIisation , a pension pIan
失业保险
and unempIoyment insurance when you're,
该怎么说？找不到新对象时
how shaII I put it, between engagements?
谢谢你使我不用那么内疚
Thanks for making it easier for me.
别傻了
Don't be ridicuIous, darIing .
拿支票后…
Take the cheque.
找那女孩
And caII your girI .
不，谢谢
No, thanks.
我有自己的支票
I've got a cheque of my own .
找新作家帮忙时…
When you get yourseIf a new writer to heIp,
你该找一个跟我同样高大的人
try and find one my size.
那么你不用修改衣服长短
That way you won't have to even shorten the sIeeves.
荷莉
HoIIy!
你好
Hey.
-你在干什么？
-很抱歉
-What are you doing? -Excuse me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你跟我认识的女孩很相似
You Iook just Iike a girI I know named HoIIy.
真的吗？
ReaIIy?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你好
H i .
你想怎样？
What do you want?
我想跟你谈谈
I want to taIk to you .
我很忙
I'm busy.
-你在干什么？
-看书
-What are you doing? -Reading .
《南美洲，富裕之境》
"South America: Land of Wealth and Promise"?
真有趣
It's very interesting .
离开这儿吧
Let's get out of here.
我说离开这儿，我有话跟你说
I said Iet's get out of here. I want to taIk to you .
你怎么了？发生何事？
What's the matter with you , anyway? What's happened?
佛烈，求你别烦着我
Fred , wiII you pIease just Ieave me aIone?
荷莉
HoIIy,
我爱你
I Iove you .
-你去哪儿？
-去女厕
-Where are you going? -To the Iadies' room .
-你怎么了？
-放开我
-What's the matter with you , anyway? -Let me go.
-不
-佛烈，求求你放开我
-No. -Fred , pIease Iet me go.
先弄清楚一件事
Let's get something straight.
我从来不是佛烈
I am not now, nor have I ever been , Fred .
也不是班尼谢克立
Nor am I Benny ShackIett, whoever he may be.
我是保罗华杰，我爱你
My name is PauI , PauI Varjak, and I Iove you .
-放开我
-等事情弄清楚后
-Let me go. -Not tiII we get this settIed .
南美洲有何特别？
Now what's aII this jazz about South America?
若我嫁给南美人…
I thought if I'm going to marry a South American ,
就要熟悉那儿
I'd better find out something about the country.
-嫁给南美人？
-荷西
-Marry? What South American? -Jos茅.
-谁是荷西？
-荷西贝雷拉
-Who the heII is Jos茅? -Jos茅 da SiIva Pereira.
他是谁？
Who the heII's Jos茅 da SiIva Pereira?
你曾见过他，梅格的朋友
DarIing , you met him . I know you did . Mag WiIdwood's friend .
跟拉斯蒂同来的高大英俊男士
The taII , good-Iooking one who came to the party with Rusty?
你不会相信
WeII , my dear, you won't beIieve this,
他不但英俊，而且很富有
but it turns out not onIy is he handsome and wiIdIy rich ,
他绝对是适合人选
he's absoIuteIy cuckoo for me.
-你疯了
-你以为我属于你的？
-You're crazy. -What? Do you think you own me?
我正是这么想
That's exactIy what I think.
其他人都这么想
I know, I know. That's what everybody aIways thinks,
但他们错了
but everybody happens to be wrong .
看，我不是其他人
Look, I am not everybody.
我是吗？
Or am I?
你真的这么想吗？
Is that what you reaIIy think?
我跟鼠辈、超级鼠辈无分别？
That I'm no different from aII your other rats and super-rats?
等等
Wait a minute.
若是这样…
If that's it,
若你有这种想法
if that's what you reaIIy think,
我有些东西想给你
there's something I want to give you .
是什么？
What's that?
五十元去女厕的费用
$50 for the powder room .
我不想叫你进来，但我不能独自…
I wouIdn't ask you in , except the pIace is in such a mess
-面对乱局
-你有口讯
-I couIdn't bear to face it aIone. -You have a message.
不
No.
行了
Ol茅.
晚安，雄志
Good evening , Mr Yunioshi .
晚安，保罗
Good evening , PauI .
晚安
Good evening .
你定要帮助我
PIease, you must heIp me.
荷莉
HoIIy.
HoIIy. HoIIy.
荷莉
HoIIy.
-荷莉
-放开我，不！
-HoIIy. HoIIy. -Let me go. No !
荷莉
HoIIy.
-荷莉
-佛烈
-HoIIy. -Fred . Fred .
荷莉
HoIIy.
不
No, no.
佛烈
Fred .
-你对她干了什么？
-没什么
-What did you do to her? -Nothing .
看了电报后她就这样
There was a teIegram , and then this.
捣乱一切，像是疯了似的
Crashing everything , conducting Iike a crazy. It's appaIIing .
我不可闹出丑闻
I can't have a pubIic scandaI . It's too deIicate.
我要顾及自己和家人的声誉
My name, my position , my famiIy.
警察会到来吗？
WiII there be the poIice again , do you think?
不会，没有法例禁止人们在家中发脾气。
I don't see why. There's no Iaw against busting up your own apartment.
-电报在哪儿？
-在那儿
-Where is the teIegram? -There it is.
“获悉佛烈在堪萨斯州莱利堡
"Received notice. Young Fred kiIIed
“交通意外中身亡
"in jeep accident, Fort RiIey, Kansas.
“丈夫和子女均深感遗憾
"Your husband and chiIdren join in the sorrow of our mutuaI Ioss.
“爱你的医生”
"Letter foIIowing . Love, Doc."
她的弟弟佛烈
Her brother Fred .
她和弟弟很亲密吗？
This brother, was she very cIose to him?
是
Yeah .
我该怎办？
What can one do?
帮助她
Try to heIp her.
我曾尝试，但帮助不大
I tried . It didn't do much good .
你在巴西有牧场？
You got a ranch or something down in BraziI , don't you?
是
Yes.
很好，她喜欢牧场
That's good . She'II Iike that.
你最好进去
WeII , you better get in there.
巴西旅游
-你好
-H i . -HeIIo.
收到你的电报，怎找到我？
Got your wire. How did you know where to reach me?
我用尽各种办法，四处打听
Oh , I tried everything . CaIIed peopIe, asked around
突然想起查电话簿
and suddenIy thought of Iooking in the phone book.
无论如何，很高兴你来了
Anyway, I'm gIad you couId come.
-你看来不错
-是吗？
-You Iook fine. -You think so?
我很胖，很久没整理发型
I'm fat as a pig , and I haven't had my hair done in months.
但我很快乐
But I'm happy, reaIIy happy. It probabIy shows.
看得出来，你容光焕发
You Iook tr猫s distingu茅 yourseIf.
近日我在写作
I got a job. I've been writing a IittIe.
我看了你三篇文章
I know. I've read three of your stories.
两篇刊在《纽约人》，一篇在杂志内
Two in The New Yorker and one in that funny IittIe magazine.
坐下来好吗？
Won't you sit down?
谢谢
Thank you .
-我在学编织
-我看到了
-I've taken up knitting . -So I see.
完成后相信会很好看
It'II probabIy Iook very nice once it's finished .
实际上我有点紧张
ActuaIIy, I'm a IittIe nervous about it.
荷西带来新牧场的蓝图
Jos茅 brought up the bIueprints for a new ranch house he's buiIding
但我觉得…
and I have this strange feeIing
我将蓝图和编织指示图混淆了
that maybe the bIueprints and my knitting instructions got switched .
我可能编织出一个牧场
I mean , it isn't impossibIe that I'm knitting a ranch house.
我不知怎告诉你我有多快乐
ReaIIy, darIing , I can't teII you how divineIy happy I am .
那是什么？
What is that, anyhow?
葡萄牙语，复杂的语言
Portuguese. A very compIicated Ianguage.
四千个不规则动词
Four thousand irreguIar verbs.
很厉害，是什么意思？
Very impressive. What's it mean?
“我相信你跟屠夫在一起”
"I beIieve you are in Ieague with the butcher."
荷莉，怎么了？
HoIIy, what's this about?
你为何想见我？
Why did you want to see me?
荷西在华盛顿
Jos茅's in Washington for the night
我想，如果我问你，你或许愿意来
so I thought if I asked you over, you might come.
我已和其他关心我的人道别
And , weII , I've said goodbye to everyone eIse I care about.
你要去别处？
You're going somewhere?
明天我要去里奥
I'm going to Rio tomorrow.
我有机票，我已跟沙里告别
I've got the pIane ticket, and I've even said goodbye to oId SaIIy.
荷西跟你一起去？
Jos茅 is fIying down with you?
我们乘坐不同班机
We're going on separate pIanes, of course.
一起前去不太好
He doesn't think it wouId Iook right for us to be traveIIing together.
他的家族很保守
H is famiIy's very important down there,
所以他介怀
so he has to worry about things Iike that.
我想由我来下厨…
Anyway, I thought I'd show off and cook dinner for us.
会很有趣
It'II be fun eating in .
我有告诉你我很快乐吗？
Did I teII you how divineIy and utterIy happy I am?
有
Yes.
接着你们会结婚？
You are getting married , then?
他还没向我求婚，不曾说那几个字
WeII , he hasn't reaIIy asked me, not in so many words.
你是指那四个字吗？
Four, you mean?
这有多难启齿
WeII , that's how many words it takes.
“请嫁给我”
"WiII you marry me?"
我知道我们会结婚
Oh , we'II get married , aII right. I know we wiII .
有他的家人在旁，在教堂举行
And in church and with his famiIy there and everything .
所以他等候至我们到里奥才说
And that's why he's waiting tiII we get to Rio, probabIy.
它像是想告诉我们一些东西
Do you think it's trying to teII us something?
希望你喜欢巧克力汁鸡饭
I hope you Iike chicken and saffron rice served with chocoIate sauce.
这是东印度传统
It's an East Indian cIassic, my dear.
三个月前我不懂打蛋
Three months ago, I couIdn't scrambIe eggs.
你没事吧？
Are you aII right?
我想你对我另眼相看
GoIIy, darIing . I did so want to impress you .
反正…
Look,
我不太喜欢有汁的鸡
I'm not much for chicken with sauce, anyway.
何不外出？我请你吃饭饯行
Why don't we go out somewhere? Let me buy you a fareweII dinner.
这会很有趣，只要那地方符合我这样的装扮。
That wouId be fun , as Iong as it's somepIace I can go Iike this.
数年后…
Years from now,
过了数年后我会回来
years and years, I'II be back.
我带着九个巴西小子
Me and my nine BraziIian brats.
他们会如荷西般黝黑
They'II be dark Iike Jos茅, of course,
但他们会有漂亮的碧眼
but they'II have bright, green , beautifuI eyes.
我会带他们回来
因为他们定要看看这儿
I'II bring them back, aII right, 'cause they must see this.
我爱纽约
Oh , I Iove New York.
那么你为何离开？你怎么想的？
Then why are you Ieaving? What's in it for you , anyway?
我知道你在想什么，我不怪你
Look, I know what you're thinking , and I don't bIame you .
我说话一向华而不实
I've aIways thrown out such a jazzy Iine.
除了医生和你，荷西是我首次真正的恋爱
ReaIIy, except for Doc and yourseIf, Jos茅's my first non-rat romance.
他不可算是我完美的如意郎君
Not that he's my idea of the absoIute finito.
他太一本正经和谨慎了
He's too prim and cautious to be my absoIute ideaI .
若我可选择任何人，我不会选荷西
Now if I couId choose from anybody aIive, I wouIdn't pick Jos茅.
尼赫鲁，或许史怀哲
Nehru , maybe, or AIbert Schweitzer.
或许伯恩斯坦
Or Leonard Bernstein .
但我为荷西疯狂
But I am mad about Jos茅.
若他提出，我愿为他戒烟
I honestIy think I'd give up smoking if he asked me.
时候不早了，我们去吃东西吧
Come on , darIing , Iet's eat. It's getting Iate.
明天就要离开，我甚至没执拾行装
I'm Ieaving tomorrow, and I haven't even begun to pack.
我不想荷西认为我是丢失钥匙的女孩
Didn't want Jos茅 to think I was the kind of girI who Ioses her key,
所以我配备二十六条钥匙
so I had 26 of them made.
等等，我有更好的提议
No, wait. I got a better idea.
作为道别仪式
Kind of a fareweII gesture.
一定是有人弄坏了门锁
Somebody must have tripped the Iock.
狡猾的雄志
Crafty deviI , that Yunioshi .
醒来，英国人来了
Wake up, wake up ! The British are coming !
-或许是巴西人
-没错
-Or, in this case, the BraziIians. -ExactIy.
-我还要清理那些饭
-ExactIy. -I've stiII got to cIean up aII that rice.
你可知道…
Hey, you know. . .
嘿
Hey!
她在那儿，那女子
There she are who did it! The wanted woman ! There !
扫毒组的克朗柏格
Groenburger. Narcotics squad .
-什么意思？
-发生何事？
-What do you mean? -What's going on?
-何不去问你的老板？
-什么老板？
-Why don't you ask your boss? -What boss?
沙里托马图，你何不问他？走吧
SaIIy Tomato. Why don't you ask him? Come on .
四处搜查，看看有没有毒品，他们有很多毒品…
Look around for narcotic. They got pIenty narcotic in there.
第十九区
-你叫什么名字？
-华杰
-What's your name? -Varjak.
留在那儿
HoId it down over there !
保罗华杰，华杰
PauI Varjak. V-A-R-J-A-K.
-嘿
-你走吧
-Hey! -Oh , get Iost, wiII you?
快离开
Get out!
我是作家
I'm a writer.
作家
W-R-I-T-E-R.
-每次问一条
-我不能回答所有问题
-PIease. One, one, pIease. -One at a time. PIease, one.
很好
Good .
-等等
-我不能回答所有问题
-Wait a minute. Wait a minute. -I can't answer aII your questions.
-每次问一条
-够了
-Just one at a time. -Knock it off!
由你开始吧
Now, darIing , why don't you start?
你曾替托马图用密码带口讯？
Is it true you carried messages from Tomato in code?
当然不是
Of course not.
我只是在汉堡天堂与奥肖内西先生见面…
I'd just meet Mr O'Shaughnessy at Hamburger Heaven
报告天气
and give him the weather report.
别问我当中的内容
SimpIy do not ask me what this is aII about.
但你曾探访托马图？
But you did used to visit Tomato?
每周都去，那又如何？
I used to see him every week. What's wrong with that?
他参与毒品买卖
WeII , you must've known Tomato was part of the narcotics syndicate.
他不曾向我提及毒品
Mr Tomato never mentioned narcotics to me.
他被诬告使我感到愤怒
It makes me furious the way aII these wretched peopIe keep persecuting him .
他是一个敏感…
He's a deepIy sensitive person .
-亲切的老人
-那么你是清白的？
-A darIing oId man . -Then you're innocent.
-当然
-你会怎么办？
-Of course I'm innocent. -What are you going to do about it?
-什么意思？
-谁是你的律师？
-What do you mean? -WeII , who's your Iawyer?
不知道
I don't know.
我想是奥肖内西先生
Mr O'Shaughnessy, I guess.
奥肖内西先生
Mr O'Shaughnessy!
快离开
Hey! Get out of here !
-好的，来吧
-快走
-AII right, come on . -Okay, move.
-来吧
-奥肖内西先生？
-Come on , then . -Mr O'Shaughnessy?
-闭嘴
-进来
-Shut up ! -Get in there.
迷人女子被捕
警方对托马图穷追猛打
迷人女子因毒品案被捕
-喂？
-保罗华杰先生？
-Yeah . -Mr Paul Varjak?
-是我
-准备跟好莱坞的伯曼先生通话
-Yeah . -Ready with Mr Berman in Hollywood.
请投入三元作首三分钟谈话费
Kindly deposit $3 for the first 3 minutes, please.
你好
Hello?
奥杰伯曼，是谁来电？
O.J . Berman here. Who's caIIing?
-伯曼先生，我是保罗华杰
-很高兴和你谈话
-Mr Berman , this is PauI Varjak. -N ice to taIk to you , kid .
华杰…
Varjak. V-A-R-J-A-K.
我是荷莉的朋友。我在纽约的派对见过你。
I'm a friend of HoIIy's. I met you at a party in New York.
-谁？
-保罗，保罗华杰
-Who? -Paul. Paul Varjak.
华…
V-A-R. . .
伯曼，我是佛烈
Mr Berman , this is Fred .
原来是佛烈
Oh , Fred baby, huh?
你致电是为了那女孩
So you're calling about the kid, huh?
一切已受控制，放松一点
Everything's under controI . Just reIax.
我跟纽约的律师谈过
I spoke to my Iawyer in New York.
他会处理一切，寄来帐单
I toId him to take care of everything , send me the biII
别公开我的名字
but to keep my name anonymous.
-什么？
-我不想别人知我和此事有关
-What? -Unknown. l don't want any part of it.
-你听到了吗？
-你的声音像是在隧道里
-You hear me? -You sound Iike you're in a tunneI .
那是高档电话的问题
It's this executive phone I have.
-什么？
-高档电话
-what? -Executive phone !
佛烈，她的保释金只需一万元
Fred baby, they onIy got her on $ 1 0, 000 baiI .
我的律师可在今早保释她，我告诉你…
My Iawyer can get her out at 1 0: 00 this morning . I'II teII you what you do.
你该去她那狗窝…
You bust into that dump she Iives in ,
收拾行装
coIIect aII her junk.
再去监狱接她
Go down to the jaiI . Get her out.
以假名替她入住饭店
Take her straight over to a hoteI under a phoney name, right?
我们不想她接触记者
You wanna keep away from the reporters as much as possibIe.
你愿意这样做吗？
Do you know what I mean? WiII you do that?
当然，伯曼
Sure, Mr Berman .
-我真的很感激你
-算了吧
-I can't teII you how much I appreciate. . . -Forget it.
我拖欠了她
I owe her something .
不该这么说，若你想知道原因…
Not that I owe her anything , I mean , if you reaIIy get right down to it,
但她是疯子
but she's a crazy.
她是骗子
She's a phoney.
但她是真正的骗子
But she's a reaI phoney.
-你明白我的意思吗？
-我明白
-Know what I mean , kid? -Yeah , I know what you mean .
-伯曼，谢谢你
-好的
-Thanks, Mr Berman . Thanks a Iot. -Right!
为何会失灵？
Why don't you behave?
晚安
Quel night.
你不在时我破门而入
I did a IittIe housebreaking whiIe you were away.
请去克雷顿饭店，八十四街和麦迪逊街交界
CIayton HoteI , driver. 84th and Madison .
奥杰认为你该避见传媒
O.J . thinks it'd be a good idea if you stayed out of sight for a whiIe.
我已带来你的物件，包括猫咪，希望他没事
I got most of your stuff here, incIuding cat. Hope he's aII right.
对
Yeah .
猫咪，你好
HeIIo, cat.
可怜的无名猫
Poor no-name sIob.
你找到机票吗？
Listen , darIing . Did you find that pIane ticket?
-在这儿，可换回现金
-你说笑吗？
-Right here. We can cash it in . -Cash it in? Are you kidding?
现在几点？
What time is it?
-刚过了十时
-好
-A IittIe after 1 0: 00. -Good .
去艾迪怀尔德机场
IdIewiId Airport, pIease, driver.
-别理会她，你不能这么做
-为什么？
-Never mind . You can't do that. -Why not?
你不明白自己现在的处境
You don't understand . You're under indictment.
你在保释期间离境会被拘捕
If they catch you jumping baiI , they'II Iock you up and throw away the key.
别说笑了
Don't be ridicuIous, darIing .
明天后…
By the day after tomorrow,
我就是巴西总统夫人
I'II be married to the future president of BraziI .
我可以获得外交豁免权
And that'II give me dipIomatic immunity or something .
看来不是
I wouIdn't bet on it.
什么？
What is it, darIing?
你有口讯
Message for you .
好的，我明白了
Oh , yes, I see.
他亲自送来…
Did he bring it in person , or was it,
还是只放在门下？
just there, shoved under the door?
由表亲送来
A cousin .
把手袋给我
Hand me my purse, wiII you , darIing?
女孩子没涂上口红不可看口讯
A girI can't read that sort of thing without her Iipstick.
你替我读出来
You read it to me, wiII you , darIing?
我承受不了
I don't think I can quite bear. . .
你真的想这样吗？
Sure you want me to?
是
Okay.
“我亲爱的小女孩
"My dearest IittIe girI ,
“我爱你，我知道你与别人不同
"I have Ioved you knowing you were not as others.
“但我不喜欢…
"But conceive of my despair
“受公众注目
"upon discovering in such a brutaI and pubIic styIe
“我和你来自不同阶级
"how very different you are from the manner of woman
“你和我心目中的妻子很不同
"a man of my position couId hope to make his wife.
“很抱歉你现在名誉受损
"I grieve for the disgrace of your present circumstances.
“我不想加深你的…
"And I do not find it in my heart
“痛楚
"to add my condemn
“因为你已被旁人指责
"to the condemn that surrounds you .
“希望你在心里不会指责我
"So I hope you wiII find it in your heart not to condemn me.
“我要保护家人及我的声誉
"I have my famiIy to protect and my name
“我是一名懦夫
"and I am a coward where these institutions enter.
“原谅我，漂亮的孩子，愿主保佑你
"Forget me, beautifuI chiId . And may God be with you .
“荷西”
"Jos茅."
怎样？
WeII?
至少他很坦白
WeII , at Ieast he's honest.
-有点感动
-感动？
-It's kind of touching . -Touching?
那守旧的人
That square-baII jazz.
他说他是懦夫
He says he's a coward .
那么他不是鼠辈或超越鼠辈
AII right. So he's not a reguIar rat or even a super-rat.
他只是受惊的小老鼠
He's just a scared IittIe mouse, that's aII .
但…
But, oh , goIIy.
天啊
Gee, damn .
不用再去南美洲
WeII , so much for South America.
你也不会成为皇后了
I didn't reaIIy think you were cut out to be queen of the Pampas, anyway.
-去克雷顿饭店
-艾迪怀尔德机场
-CIayton HoteI . -IdIewiId .
什么？
What?
班机十二时开出，我会上机
The pIane Ieaves at 1 2: 00. And on it I pIan to be.
荷莉，你不能去
HoIIy, you can't.
我不是想去追回荷西
I'm not hotfooting it after Jos茅, if that's what you think. Oh , no.
他成为总统与我无关
As far as I'm concerned , he's the future president of nowhere.
但我为何要浪费这机票？
OnIy why shouId I waste a perfectIy good pIane ticket?
我不曾到过巴西
Besides, I've never been to BraziI .
求求你，别这样看着我
PIease, darIing , don't sit there Iooking at me Iike that.
我一定要去
I'm going and that's aII there is to it.
他们只是…
Now aII they want from me
想我指证沙里
are my services as the state's witness against SaIIy.
没有人想起诉我
Nobody has any intention of prosecuting me.
但他们没有机会这么做
To begin with , they don't have a ghost of a chance.
我对这城市不再留恋
Even so, this town's finished for me.
至少在短时间内
At Ieast for a whiIe.
聚光灯会伤害女孩的皮肤
There are certain shades of IimeIight that can wreck a girI's compIexion .
我到每间发廊也会受大众注视
They'II have the rope up at every saIoon in town .
我告诉你该怎么做
I'II teII you what you do for me, darIing .
你回去之后…
When you get back to town ,
致电《纽约时报》
I want you to caII up the New York Times or whoever you caII .
我要你把巴西五十富豪的名单寄给我
I want you to maiI me a Iist of the 50 richest men in BraziI .
是五十富豪
The 50 richest.
-我不会让你这么做
-你不会让我这么做？
-HoIIy, I'm not going to Iet you do this. -You're not going to Iet me?
荷莉，我爱你
HoIIy, I'm in Iove with you .
-那又如何？
-So what? -So what?
这是很重要的
So pIenty.
-我爱你，你属于我
-不
-I Iove you . You beIong to me. -No.
-人们不属于对方
-他们当然是
-PeopIe don't beIong to peopIe. -Of course they do.
没有人可将我放在笼内
I'm not gonna Iet anyone put me in a cage.
我不想将你放在笼内，我想爱你
I don't want to put you in a cage. I want to Iove you .
-两者是相同的
-不，不是的
-It's the same thing . -No, it's not.
-荷莉
-我不是荷莉
-HoIIy. . . -I'm not HoIIy.
也不是露拉美，我不知道自己是谁
I'm not LuIa Mae, either. I don't know who I am .
我跟这只猫一样
I'm Iike cat, here.
我和猫咪都是无名氏，不属于任何人
We're a coupIe of no-name sIobs. We beIong to nobody.
也没人属于我们
我们甚至不属于对方
And nobody beIongs to us. We don't even beIong to each other.
停车
Stop the cab.
你认为怎样？
What do you think?
这儿该适合你
This ought to be the right kind of pIace for a tough guy Iike you .
垃圾堆，充满老鼠
Garbage cans, rats gaIore.
滚开
Scram !
我说下车
I said take off! Beat it!
起程吧
Let's go.
司机
Driver
请停在那儿
puII over here.
你知道你有何问题吗？无名氏小姐
You know what's wrong with you , Miss Whoever-you-are?
你很懦弱，缺乏勇气
You're chicken . You've got no guts.
你害怕承认人生就是这样
You're afraid to stick out your chin and say, "Okay, Iife's a fact."
人们相爱
PeopIe do faII in Iove.
结成佳偶
PeopIe do beIong to each other
因为这是人们获得真正幸福的唯一机会
because that's the onIy chance anybody's got for reaI happiness.
你说自己野性难驯
You caII yourseIf a free spirit, a wiId thing .
害怕别人将你困在笼子里
And you're terrified somebody's going to stick you in a cage.
其实你已在笼子里是你一手做成的
WeII , baby, you're aIready in that cage. You buiIt it yourseIf.
这和图纳、德州…
And it's not bounded in the west by TuIip, Texas
或索马里无关
or in the east by SomaIiIand .
而是看你自己怎么想
It's wherever you go.
无论去哪儿，你也会遇到自己
Because no matter where you run , you just end up running into yourseIf.
给你的，这数个月我一直带在身边
Here. I've been carrying this thing around for months.
我不再需要它
I don't want it any more.
猫咪，过来
Here, cat!
猫咪
Cat!
猫咪在哪儿？
Where's the cat?
我不知道
I don't know.
猫咪
Cat!
Cat.
猫咪
剧终
Mandarin